# GRANT BRITCHFORD

## **Professional Summary**

Student at Code Institute studying a level 5 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development with a preferred specialization in Data Analytics. I am dedicated to improving my skills with firsthand learning and development work and am adept at HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and Python and other programming languages. Well organized and an efficient communitive and analytical team collaborator.

## Education

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development,

09/2023 - Current

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland

I am currently halfway through a level 5 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development with a preferred specialization in Data Analytics.

NVQ Level 2, Engineering Manufacture,

09/1994 - 09/1997

 $\label{eq:continuous} \begin{tabular}{l} Engineering Training Authority-Southampton, \\ Hampshire \\ \end{tabular}$ 

<u>City & Guilds, Fabrication, Welding & Engineering Competences,</u>

09/1994 - 09/1997

Southampton City College – Southampton, Hampshire

11 GCSE's

12/1989 - 09/1994

Alderman Quilley School - Eastleigh, Hampshire

## Languages

English - Fluent

French-Elementary

## Contact

Address: Bicester, Oxfordshire

**Phone: +44** 07831 572214

Email: grant.britchford@hotmail.co.uk

Nationality: White British

GitHub: www.github.com/grant-britchford

**LinkedIn:** www.linkedin.com/in/grant-britchford-211623292

Open to Hybrid & Remote work.

## Skills

#### Software Development

- > HTML5
- > CSS3
- ➤ JavaScript
- > Python
- > SQL

#### **Data Analytics**

- > Analytical Charts
- Data Analysis
- > Dashboard Building & Designing
- ➤ Descriptive Analysis

#### **Programs**

- Microsoft Excel
- ➤ Microsoft PowerPoint
- > Heroku
- > Google sheets
- ➤ Google Cloud Platform
- > Jupyter Notebook
- Anaconda
- ➤ Wireframe Sketcher
- ➤ GitHub

#### **Project**

- > Project Management
- > Project Planning
- Project Design

## Website Projects

#### Truants Car Club

This is a website designed for a fictional classic car club that organizes events around the UK to show case their cars.

Designed using HTML and CSS.

https://grant-britchford.github.io/Truants-Car-Club

#### **Eddies Ironworks**

This is a backend web program used by a fictious steelwork shop to track their sales and stock data.

Designed using Python, Google sheets and Google Cloud Platform

www.github.com/grant-britchford/Eddies-Ironworks

https://eddiesironworks-de86615814ee.herokuapp.com

#### Ultimate Horror Quiz

An online quiz app with 20 questions with multiple answers and a 10 second time limit with each question. Questions based on real life serial killers and the books and movies they influenced.

Designed using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

https://grant-britchford.github.io/Ultimate-Horror-Quiz

## **Data Analysis Projects**

#### Advanced Excel

The project is based on core data showing dates, products, regions and sales.

www.linkedin.com/posts/grant-britchford-211623292 oeson-ogtip-aritridebnath-activity-7157400375380070401i5rM?utm\_source=share&utm\_medium=member\_desktop

#### Statistical Project

This project is based on the 2018-2023 stock values of Microsoft, Apple and Tesla vs the S&P 500

www.linkedin.com/posts/grant-britchford-211623292 oeson-ogtip-aritridebnath-activity-7165046247966388224-PLPS??utm source=share&utm medium=memebe r\_desktop

## Team Projects

Halloween Hackathon Project building a interactive website showing Halloween events for family, teens and adults

Designed using HTML, CSS, Python and JavaScript

https://github.com/Kaylaesmith1/hackathon-octteam6

## Work Experience

#### Data Analyst Intern

01/2024 - Current

Oeson Ltd - Remote, UK

- Supported back-end infrastructure by managing web APIs and Azure SQL databases.
- Employed advanced knowledge of Excel, from SUMIF to INDEX MATCH and power queries.
- ➤ Identified trends and generated insights by conducting routine analyses of various data.
- ➤ Enhanced strategic decision making by generating and analyzing sales and customer behavior models.
- > Extracted and presented sales and product data from inventory database to enable financial forecasting.

#### Career Break

10/2022 - 09/2023

Taken due to ill health.

#### Sole Trader, Britchford Fabrication & Welding

08/2005 - 10/2022

Bicester, Oxfordshire

- > Customer Communications
- ➤ Manage Staff Requirements
- > Project Design
- > Project Management
- > Material Management